Robert H. Taylor Collection of English and American Literature, 1280s-1958 (bulk 1800s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 3: Modern Manuscripts (Unbound) and Correspondence, 1545-1969; 23 archival boxes
  - Campbell, Thomas, 1777-1844, 1801-1839; 2 folders
    - 32 letters 1801-1837: 1 to I. Bowing; 1 to James Currie; 1 to H.M. Dyer; 1 to Thomas Hill Esq; 3 to Alexander Ireland; 1 to J. Millar; 1 to Robert Montgomery, 1 to Edward Moxon; 7 to John Richardson; 1 to W. Smith; 1 to William Sotheby, and 14 to various others, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - manuscript of poem, "Naval Ode" that begins "Ye Mariners of England...," 1 page, 1839; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - manuscript of poem, "Song" that begins "When Napoleon was flying," 1 page, undated, addressed to Messrs. Bentley, Printers, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - manuscript of poem, "Lines to Mrs. Charles Denham" 1832, addressed to Messrs. Bentley, Printers, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881, 1829-1865; 1 folder
    - 5 letters: 1 to Robert Browning, 1841 1 letter to John Chapman, 1847; 1 to J. R. Thompson, 1846; 1 to Prof. Wilson, 1829, with typed copy; 1 to unnkown recipient, 1865; signed page authorizing payment, 1856, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Carter, Elizabeth, 1717-1806, 1751-1758; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Miss Highmore," 1751 1 letter to Samuel Richardson, 1758, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Carter, Mary - manuscript????, undated; 1 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cartwright, William, 1611-1643, undated; 1 folder
    - manuscript of a 3-line Latin exhortation against book thieves, 1 p., undated; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cavendish, Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire, 1913; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Benjamin West, 1913; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of, 1694-1773, 1725-1763; 2 folders
    - 3 letters circa 1725-1763 1 to [Mrs. Henrietta Howard, Countess of Suffolk?], 1 (in French) to "Monsieur," 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 8 letters 1739-1741: 1 to "Dear Boy," 1 to "My Lord," 5 to unidentified persons, 1 to Carew Hunt by Bonamy Dobree about Chesterfield, 1934, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Churchill, Sarah, Duchess of Marlborough, 1713; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Lady Kildare, 1713; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cibber, Colley, 1671-1757, 1754; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to [Samuel Richardson], 1754; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Clairemont, Clara Mary Jane, 1798-1879, 1845; 1 folder
    - 1 letter (incomplete) to [Mary Shelley], 1845; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Clare, John, 1793-1864, 1827-1830; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Henry T. Ryde (with "The Gipsey Song" poem), 1827 1 letter to John Taylor, 1830, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Clark, Mary Cowden, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "My dear Enthusiast and Father-in-love," and postscript to "Mrs. Balmacas(?),"1857, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cobbett, William, 1762-1835, undated; 1 folder
    - manuscript of verse, "American Independence," 1 p., undated; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Coke, Edward, Sir, 1552-1634, 1603; 1 folder
    - 3 letters by Thomas Sackville, 1603; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834, 1801-1863; 2 folders
    - 9 letters 1806-1863: 1 to Charles Aders (includes poem), 1 to Washington Allston, 1 to J. H. Frere, 1 to Rev. T. Methuen, [James Perry], 1 to J. Pettigrew, and 1 to unidentified person, 1 letter to an unidentified person concerning a manuscript which had been submitted for his opinion, circa 1826, 1 letter to "Dear Madam", circa 1817, 1 letter to a publisher, circa 1818, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 2 manuscripts of verse 1833: "Love's Apparition and Evanishment, an Allegoric Romance," 2 pp., and another copy written in Coleridge's letter to Aders, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 12 letters 1801-1834: 1 to Mrs. Aders, 1 to Miss Belham, 2 to James Gellman (1 includes verses), 1 to Greenough, 1 to Thomas Hurst, 2 to Mr. Mudford, 1 to Mr. Ridout, 1 to F. Wrangham, 1 (fragment) to "My dear Henry," 1 ticket (small card), portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - 2 manuscripts of verse, "Maid of my love! sweet Genevieve!" sonnet and "God's Omnipresence, a Hymn," 1814 1 document, 1 p., 1805 1 autograph manuscript copy of Coleridge's "Inscription for a Fountain on a Heath," copied by William Cullen Bryant on 1860 November 1, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Collins, William Wilkie, 1824-1889, 1860-1875; 2 folders
    - 4 letters 1860-1875: 1 to Nugent Robinson, 1 to Sampson & Low, and 2 to Anthony Trollope, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The Clergyman's Confession, 1875; 1 folder
      - Manuscript of short story, 19 leaves, circa 1875; 1 item (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Colman, George, 1732-1794, 1785; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Henry Temple, Second Viscount Palmerston, 1785; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Combe, William, 1742-1823, 1780; 1 folder
    - Manuscript of verse, "Answer from the Hon:ble J. Townshend on Board the Courageux to his Friend the Hon:ble J. C. Fox Partridge-Shooting," attributed to Combe, 6 pp., circa 1780; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 21)
      [see: Tickell, Richard, 1551-1793 folder for the related poem by Tickell]
  - Congreve, William, 1670-1729, 1720; 1 folder
    - 1 document, 1720 2 letters (1769-1770) to Rev. Dr. W. Percy, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924, 1915-1925; 1 folder
    - 5 letters 1915-1925: 1 letter to Richard Garnett, [1920], 1 letter to Mr. Robertson, 1915, with an accompanying letter by Richard Curle, 1 letter to "Dearest Dick", [1925]; 1 typed and signed letter from Conrad to Ford with holograph additions by Conrad; 1 holograph cover sheet labeled "Joseph Conrad, A Personal Reminiscence, Frontispiece, Letter J. S. C., 18 Nov.'23" with a holograph note by Ford Madox Ford describing the letter and the reason for selling it., 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Coolbrith, Ina, 1842-1928, 1904; 1 folder
    - manuscript of verse, "Somewhere the seed must spring...," 1 p., 1904; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Cooper, James Fenimore, 1789-1851, 1826-1848; 2 folders
    - 6 letters 1826-1848: 1 letter to an unidentified person, undated 1 to "Dear Fagan" (his publisher), 1848; 2 letters to Lady Dowry from Cooper's secretary announcing his inability to attend, undated 1 letter, not signed and undated to "Mr. Editor"; 1 letter in French, to "M. le Préfét du department du Rhone", Sept. 26, 1826, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - 1 leaf of a manuscript of "Waterwitch", vol. 1, chapter I; 2 checks singed by Cooper to Harry Marvin, on Ostego County Bank, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 25A)
  - Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924, 1892-1918; 1 folder
    - 6 letters 1892-1918: 1 letter to "Fraulein Hummel," 1894; 1 letter to Lady Francis Balfour, 1910; 2 letters to Sir Charles Hall, 1892, 1893; 1 letter to Messrs. Dodd, Mead & Co., 1906, with typed transcript; 1 letter to Sheffrington, 1896, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cornford, Frances Crofts, 1886-1958, 1955; 1 folder
    - 2 letters to David Garnett, 1955; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cowley, Abraham, 1618-1667, 1645-1656; 2 folders
    - 1 letter to "Monsieur Chevalier Browne", 1645; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, 1656; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Cowley, Hannah, 1743-1809, 1801; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to [Richard] Phillips, 1801; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Cowper, William, 1731-1800, 1783-1793; 1 folder
    - 5 letters 1783-1793: 2 to R[ichard] Phillips, one (1793) of which is cited in a 1835 letter by Robert Southey to "Dear Sir"; 1 to "My dear friend"; 1 (fragment) to unidentified person; 1 letter to Lady Hesketh with a draft of his translation of the Iliad on verso. (This is a draft of the letter of May 30, 1796 which was printed by Ryskamp and King, IV p. 459.), portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Manuscript of poem, "On the Queen's nocturnal visit to London, 1789 March 17" 1 leaf, 1789, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Crabbe, George, 1754-1832, 1788-1831; 2 folders
    - 4 letters 1805-1818: 1 letter to Mr. Colburn, Aug. 3, 1817; 1 to Lackington & Co. Booksellers; 1 to [Henry-Richard Fox]; 1 to Mary Leadbetter, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 1 manuscript of a sermon, "6 Gallations 7 Verse," 18 pp., 1827; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Autograph letters and manuscripts, 1788-1831; 1 folder
      - 13 letters 1788-1831:1 note (in third person) to "Mr. J. Ball"; 4 to his son; 3 to Mr. [James] Dodsley and 1 note from Dodsley to Crabbe; 1 to Edmund Cartwright; 1 to "My dear George"; 1 to "My Lord"; 1 to "Dear Sir", portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - 2 manuscripts of verse: "[Union]" and "[Revival]," 2 poems on 1 leaf, undated fragments in Crabbe's hand, 34 pp., various sizes, portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Crabbe, George, 1785-1857, 1837; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to F. H. Lister, 1837; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "Crabbe, Geo.", 1883; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "My dear Brooke", 1883; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Crane, Stephen, 1871-1900, 1896; 1 folder
    - 2 letters: 1 to Dewitt Miller, 1896; 1 to E. Leslie Gililams, undated, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1854-1909, 1888-1908; 1 folder
    - 8 letters: 6 to John E. Reid and W.M. Collee, 1894-1908; 1 to "Mr. Reynolds," 1903; 1 to unknown recipient, 1888, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811 (AM 2002-35), undated; 1 folder
    - 2 letters: 1 to to David Garrick, undated; 1 to Tpwnshend, undated, 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Dana, Richard Henry, Jr., 1815-1882, 1855-1884; 1 folder
    - 5 letters 1855-1884: 1 letter to Charles Gilpin, 1865; 1 letter to Mr. Jos. N. Girard, June 13, 1855; 3 letters to Edward L. Pierce, 1875, 1881, and 1884; 1 note signed, admission ticket to Edward L. Pierce, April 19, 1875, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Defoe, Daniel, 1661?-1731, 1705-1708; 2 folders
    - 1 letter to [Charles Spencer?], 1708 1 document?, 1707, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Autograph letter: to Edward Owen, 1705; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - De la Mare, Walter, 1873-1956, 1905-1954; 3 folders
    - Correspondence I, 1932-1953; 1 folder
      - 19 letters 1932-1953: 2 letters (1951-1953) to Sydney Cockerell; 4 letters to Anna Robeson Burr, 1935-1938; 6 letters to Miss Julian Orde commenting on her poetry, April 29, 1944 to Sept. 3, 1945; 7 letters to Miss Winkworth, 1932, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence II, 1945-1954; 1 folder
      - 30 letters (1919-1944) to Thomas Moult; 9 TLsS (one secretarial with the signature clipped away), 7 AlsS and 2 ACsS. A friendly series of literary correspondence addressed to Marjorie Lyon, 1945-1954; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts (verse), 1905-1913; 1 folder
      - "Christina Rossetti," 6 stanzas, 1 p., 1905; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - "Winter," 2 stanzas, 1 p., 1913; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - "The Visitor," p.64 of an anthology, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - "Twice Lovely," p.82 of an anthology, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - De Quincey, Thomas, 1785-1859, 1821-1856; 3 folders
    - 9 letters 1823-1856: 4 to daughter Florence, 1 to daughter Emily, 1 to [William Tait], 1 (with corrected galley proofs) to [J. A. Hessey], 1 to unidentified person, 1 letter, unaddressed, 1853, includes an engraving of John Elwes, autograph manuscript, 2 pp, from "A Manchester Swedenborgian," first published in Tait's Magazine, Feb. 1837, as "A Literary Novitiate.", 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Autograph letters 1821-1839: 1 to Robert Chambers, 1 to [John Taylor and J. A. Hessey], 2 to unidentified persons, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Autograph letter to John Taylor, 1821; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Devereux, Robert, 2nd Earl of Essex, 1588; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Richard Bagot, 1588; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dickens, Charles John Huffam, 1812-1870, 1836-1912; 10 folders
    - Correspondence - A-B, 1840-1862; 1 folder
      - 9 letters 1840-1862: 1 to Percival W. Bankes, 1 to "Miss Barrow," 1 to "Mr. Bennett"(?), 1 to "Rev. Beusher"(?), 2 to Lady [Marguerite Gardiner] Blessington, 1 to [Boyle], 1 to "Mr. Bradbury"(?), 1 to Henry Burnett, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - C, 1836-1868; 1 folder
      - 12 letters 1836-1868 1 to Nahum Capen, 1 to "Mrs. Cattermole," 2 to Edward Chapman, 1 to Frederic Chapman, 1 to Chapman and Hall, 1 to William Clement, 1 to Thomas Cooper, 1 to George Craik, 1 to "Mr. Crewe" 1836 2 to George Cruikshank, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - D-F, 1842-1865; 1 folder
      - 10 letters 1842-1865: 1 to "The Reverend The Dean of St. Sauls"(?), 1 to F. M. Evans, 3 to [Professor] C. C. Felton, 1 to "Dear Esther," 1 to "Miss Firth," 1 to Edward Fitzgerald, 1 to "Dear [Percy] Fitzgerald," 1 to "My Dear Fred"(?), 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - G-H, 1845-1867; 1 folder
      - 13 letters 1845-1867: 1 to Elizabeth Gaskell, 6 to The Rev. M. Gilson, 2 to Mrs. [Catherine] Gore (1 in third person), 1 to "Georgina" [Hogarth?], 1 to Doctor S. G. Howe 1867, 1 to William Howitt 1859, 1 to the Head Station Master, Charing Cross, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - J-P, 1841-1865; 1 folder
      - 11 letters 1841-1865: 1 to William Jerden [1842],1 to Fanny Kemble, 1 to Ebenezer Landells, 1 to Mark [Lemon], 1 to "Miss Lewis," 1 to Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1 to Cornelius Mathews, 1 to "Dearest Mamie" (daughter?), 1 to John A. Overs, 1 to A.C. M. Parisot, 1 to Marguerite [Power], 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence - R-T, 1840-1867; 1 folder
      - 7 letters 1840-1867 1 to lady John Russell, 2 to Clarkson Stanfield (1 co-signed by John Forster), 1 to Sir Thomas Noon Talfourd, 1 to William Makepeace Thackeray, 1 to Anthony Trollope, 1 to T. Adolphus Trollope, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence - W-on, 1856-1866; 1 folder
      - 4 letters (): 1 to "Mrs. Watson," 1 to W. H. Wills 1856 2 to Mrs. Henry Wood 1864-1866, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1842-1912; 1 folder
      - 2 letters about Dickens 1853-1912 1 by Georgina Hogarth to C. C. Felton, 1 by E. V. C. Boyle to Frank Redway; 1 undated fragment in Dickens' hand to an unidentified person, portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - "A Family Party" (invitation?), 1842; 1 p. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Pickwick Papers, 1836; 1 folder
      - (Autograph) manuscript of leaf 70, 2 pp., 1836; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - To the Captain of the Britannia, 1842 January 21; 1 folder
      - Original manuscript minutes of the impromptu meeting held on board the Steamship Britannia to honor the captain, John Hewett, for bringing the passengers safely to port in Boston after a "more than ordinarily tempestuous passage," signed Charles Dickens, undated; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Dickens, Sir Henry Fielding, 1899; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Madam", 1899; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886, 1840-1958; 2 folders
    - 1 letter to "Mr. and Mrs. Hills," 1878 and 3 manuscripts, 1 folder
      - first draft of a short poem on summer, beginning "Summer laid her simple hat ...," 8 lines on slip of paper, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - "March," beginning "We like March ...," 2 pp., #1213 in her complete poems (version of 1872), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Autograph manuscript in six lines "How strange that Nature ...", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Poems and letters, 1840-1958; 1 folder
      - ["Arbutus"], beginning "Pink-small-and punctual ...," circa1875, 1 p., #1332 of her complete poems, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - "Dying! To be afraid of thee ...," circa1864, 2 pp., #831 of her complete poems, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - "The overtakelessness of those ...," undated 2 pp., #1691 of her complete poems, portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - "To this World she returned ...," 1864 2 pp., #830 of her complete, portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - "So set its Sun in thee ..." (fair copy transcribed by Susan Dickinson), circa1864, 1 p., with unidentified fragment on verso, #808 of her complete poems, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - 5 letters 1840-1882: 1 letter to "Dear Friend," 1 to [Thomas Wentworth Higginson]; 3 letters from Adele Allen, 1940 concerning Emily Dickinson; 1 autograph note from Dickinson to Mrs. Jonathan L. Jenkins, published in Thomas M. Johnson's The Letters of Emily Dickinson, vol. III, 1958 p. 767; newspaper clipping "Around Amherst", portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Doddridge, Philip, 1773-1832, 1747; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to [Edinburgh publisher David Wilson], 1747; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge (Lewis Carroll), 1882; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "My dear Bell", 1882; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Dodsley, Robert, 1703-1764, undated; 1 folder
    - prose, "One Word for the Country-Gentlemen or an Examination into the Consequences of the Enlarging of Farms," (in unknown hand), 12 pp., in paper wrappers, with "Printed for the Public, and delivered by Mr. Dodsey" written on the cover, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Donne, John, 1572-1631, 1613; 1 folder
    - poem, "Meditation on a good friday rydinge from London into ye west countrey" (copy in hand of Sir Nathaniel Rich of Donne's poem "Good Friday, 1613 Riding Westward"), 1 p., undated; 2 photographs of a portrait of Donne and 1 clipping concerning the portrait, undated, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Douglas, Alfred Bruce, Lord, 1870-1945, 1917; 1 folder
    - poetry, "Halcedama," AMsS, 2 pp., dated May 20, 1917, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 27A)
  - Douglas, Norman, 1868-1952, 1927-1941; 1 folder
    - Letters and manuscript: 6 letters 1927-1941 2 letters and 1 card to Edward Hutton; 2 letters to his son, Robin Douglas, sent from Florence, 1929, 1930 with transcripts; 1 letter to Elmer Adler, 1931 August 17 with a typescript of "Summer Islands", 56 pp., 1930 which also includes 8 photographs, and a cover letter to return to Douglas, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir, 1859-1930, 1920-1929; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1920-1929 1 to "My dear Appleton," 1 to unidentified person, 1 card to Hesketh Pearson; 1 letter to Mrs. Huddart, 1920 July 6 typed copy of a postcard to Sutton Esq. concerning war bonds, undated, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Doyle, Richard, 1824-1883, undated; 1 folder
    - 3 letters undated 1 to Matthew James Higgins, 1 to unidentified person (engraver); 1 letter to Tom Taylor illustrated with an original pen and ink drawing of himself at the Royal Academy waiting for Taylor, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Dryden, John, 1631-1700, 1666; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to Sir Robert Long, 1666; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Dufferin, Helen Selina Sheridan, Countess of, 1807-1867, undated; 1 folder
    - verse, "Prologue written by Lady Dufferin for the Amateur Theatricals at Lord Cowley's spoken by Mr. Henry Greville & Mr. Charles Sheridan," 2 pp., undated with a copy of the printed program, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dyer, George, 1755-1841, 1809; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, 1809; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Edgeworth, Maria, 1767-1849, 1814-1837; 1 folder
    - 9 letters 1814-1837: 1 to "Captain Beaufort," 1 to Major Edgeworth (cousin), 1 to Charles Fox, 2 to booksellers, 1 (in third person) to the "Editor of Friendship's Offering"; 1 letter to Archibald Constable, August 13, 1823; 1 letter to Mrs. Andrews Norton, 1837 December 1 with transcripts of the same; 1 letter to Mrs. Joseph Wedgwood, 1814 January 1 5 pp., 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Eliot, George, 1819-1880, 1829-1869; 3 folders
    - Includes an unpublished letter by Eliot to Alfred Austin, as well as correspondence between Kathleen Adams, secretary of the George Eliot Fellowship, and H. W. Woodward, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 2 letters: 1 by "Marian E. Lewes" (Eliot) about the success of Adam Bede, 1829; 1 to "Dear Madam", 1864, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - J. B. Payne meets George Eliot and her husband, 1869; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 27)
      Notes on meeting George Eliot and her husband at their home on Wednesday, 17 February 1869: autograph manuscript, 5 leaves (5 pages of text), signed by J. B. Payne
  - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965, 1922-1956; 2 folders
    - 8 letters 1922-1947: 6 letters to Leonard Woolf, 1 letter to Richard J[ennings], 1 letter to R. J. Schoek, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence 1947-1956: 18 letters (1897-1956) to Elizabeth Jungmann (Max Beerbohm's second wife); 1 postcard from the Eliots to Lady Beerbohm; 4 letters and one color lithograph Christmas card, by Barnett Freedman, from Eliot to Miss Elizabeth Horton, Dec. 7, 1948 - March 20, 1950; 1 letter to Mrs. Violet Schiff, 1 telegram to "Thompson," 1 canceled check from Jungmann to Eliot, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Elizabeth I, Queen of England, 1533-1603, 1562; 1 folder
    - 1 document, 1562; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882, 1839-1904; 2 folders
    - 12 letters 1839-1872: 1 letter to Mrs. Arnold, 1856; 1 letter to "My dear Blake", with transcription, Aug. 26, 1852; 1 letter to Titus Coan, 21 May, 1876; 1 letter to Mr. Dickinson, 1856; 1 letter to Wendell Phillips, Sept. 23, 1866; 1 letter to George B. Sherman, 1835; 1 letter to the editor Mr. Underwood referring to his essay Books, with typescript of the same; 3 letter to Charles Stearns Wheeler, March-June 1829;1 letter from Fanny Ripley to Mrs. Chapin, transmitting a copy of Emerson's "Letters & Social Aims," [1876]; Photocopy of letter to S. P. Chase, Secretary of the Treasury, 1863, on behalf of Walt Whitman; 1 letter, unaddressed, 1867, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 2 manuscripts: "English Traits," 1 p., circa 1862 and "Hymn", a poem, 2 pp. 2 postcards, one of a portrait of Emerson, and one of his home in Massachusetts; photographs, lithographs, steel engravings, and portraits of Emerson; miscellaneous papers, correspondence, and magazine clippings about Emerson, 1904 heavily corrected page proofs of Emerson's "Essay on Character," with a holograph page insert and an autograph note signed to the printer, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7A)
  - Evelyn, John, 1620-1706, 1694; 2 folders
    - 3 letters: 1 (draft) to Samuel Pepys, 1 to unidentified person,1 by Sir William Coventry, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1 letter to Samuel Pepys, 1694; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Evelyn, John, The Younger, 1655-1699, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 manuscript of poem. 2 pp., undated; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Fanshawe, Richard, Sir, 1608-1666, 1640; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Honest Jacke" [John Heath], 1640; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754, 1725-1745; 3 folders
    - 1 letter to John Nourse, 1738; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - 1 document: affadavit, 1725; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - 1 manuscript: "Sanctuary," 1 p., circa 1745; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fielding, Sarah, 1710-1768, undated; 1 folder
    - 2 letters (1758-1759) to Samuel Richardson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fitzgerald, Edward, 1809-1883, 1835-1883; 4 folders
    - Correspondence I - 7 letters (1873-1883) to "Miss Biddell", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 16)